Previously on Captain Tsubasa.
Ozora Tsubasa, who loves football dearly...
...happens upon a dispute over a football field in his new town.
It is between Wakabayashi Genzo and Ishizaki Ryo.
With his brimming confidence, Wakabayashi, who has never conceded a goal...
...nullifies all the attempts of the students Ishizaki gathered.
The performance Wakabayashi displayed...
...captivates Tsubasa's interest...
...and he challenges him!
Wakabayashi, glad you came!
This is the one who challenged you!
Don't be ridiculous!
A newcomer like him can't kick that powerfully!
Whether it's true or not, we'll see the answer right now!
Here!
Watch out! Here it comes!
Was it fate or coincidence?
In any case, Ozora Tsubasa and Wakabayashi Genzo had met.
How about that, Wakabayashi?!
You've seen his real power now!
# Ozora Tsubasa requests a match #
Will you accept my challenge?
Why do you challenge me?
He saw you saving shots from the rugby and baseball players the other day.
Is that so.
Captain!
Was it you guys?
What happened?
Weren't you going to head home?
Perfect timing.
That kid kicks pretty hard.
But if he thinks that alone is enough to play football, he's sorely mistaken.
What?!
If you want to challenge me...
...you must get past all of them by yourself!
What?!
Only then will I accept your challenge!
Episode 2: Flying!
Translation: ARE-YOU-SURE
www.areyousuresubs.com
Captain, what's the meaning of this?
As I said.
You will follow my orders.
Alright, but...
Who's that shrimp?
# Ozora Tsubasa requests a match #
What's this?
He launched this ball all the way from a very far distance to my home.
So you're going to accept this challenge, Captain?
Yes, exactly.
Hey, Wakabayashi!
Tsubasa wants to challenge you!
Making him take on the entire B team all alone is absurd!
If he doesn't want to do it, he can just go home.
You're so unfair, Wakabayashi!
I'll do it.
What?! You will? Are you serious?
Because he's about to accept my challenge.
But hold on! You're one against that many!
I didn't quite catch what's going on, but it looks fun.
He's got guts to challenge the Captain.
He's already lost.
Don't worry. Leave it to me.
What?
Truly a strange kid.
Hey, Tsubasa!
Just realized...
...can you play in those shoes?
Yes. Right now I only have these with me.
What? That's impossible.
Even if they're the B team, they're pretty good.
Plus you're alone. Two disadvantages at once.
You're like a bird with broken wings.
But...
Does anyone have extra cleats? Lend him some.
O-Okay.
Thank you, Wakabayashi-kun.
I don't need your thanks.
I'm only doing this so you can't blame the cleats when you lose.
Then it's time for the challenge.
I'm sure I've seen that man somewhere.
I wonder if he'll manage.
Can you see?
The one who brought you here.
His name is Wakabayashi-kun.
He's talking to the ball again.
He won last year's national championship without conceding a single goal.
So he's a magnificent goalkeeper.
But first I have to get past the other players...
...so I can challenge that goalkeeper.
What's he rambling about?
He's talking to the ball.
He's clearly nuts.
You saved my life when I was very little...
...but I need your help again.
I want to challenge him at all costs.
What are you waiting for?!
Hurry up and get the ball!
O-Okay!
Alright, let's go!
Okay!
Ready?
Let's go.
Come on!
What?
He got past three players instantly!
What is this?
Taking a shot from under the bus...
These dribbles...
Even at this young age...
...he's already become friends with the ball!
No doubt about it.
This kid...
That's the kid!
Go, Tsubasa!
Damn...
Don't let him shoot! Block him!
He's flying!
What?!
Go in!
The ball is still in play!
It might be a bit of a waste, but...
...this contest is worth a little whiskey!
I knew it, that man...
...is the forward for the Brazilian national team...
...Roberto Hongo!
Finish the cross!
This was how the first challenge between
...Ozora Tsubasa and Wakabayashi Genzo came to be.
No one could have known that this would later...
...lead Japanese football to tremendous heights!
That's it! Goal!
Genzo!
Captain!
Get a grip.
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
Don't touch me!
What's the matter with you, Wakabayashi?!
Shut up!
Hey, he's bleeding.
Captain!
Genzo!
I lost.
I lost to this shrimp.
Ozora Tsubasa, isn't it?
Yes.
A match.
What?
We'll play a match, a match!
This challenge can't be settled like this!
Only a match can decide it!
I'll accept your challenge at the interschool tournament!
Interschool?
Wait, Wakabayashi!
Listen!
In the interschool tournament, if you score even one goal...
...I'll admit defeat.
Alright, I understand.
It doesn't matter who wins the match.
We'll see if you can score a goal against me!
Translation: ARE-YOU-SURE
www.areyousuresubs.com
Ishizaki.
Until the interschool tournament, use this field.
Do some training...
...so you don't get rusty.
Let's go!
Yes, sir!
Hey, wait!
The cleats, the cleats.
R-Right...
I don't want them!
Thanks for the cleats.
You're welcome.
See you at the interschool tournament!
Wakabayashi really lost it, huh.
I thought he was going to hit you.
But scoring that goal was truly great.
Thanks.
You actually managed to get it in.
Ishizaki-kun!
Here.
Sorry.
I may not look it, but I'm the captain of the Nankatsu football team.
Ishizaki-kun, pass!
Okay!
Next time, I'll introduce you to the team.
Okay, thanks.
By the way, what's this interschool tournament they were talking about?
That?
First, remember that Nankatsu and Shutetsu are rivals!
Rivals?
Yes. That wretched Shutetsu!
Their football team is very good.
All the good players are with them...
...while we only have the lousy ones!
Between Nankatsu and Shutetsu, there's nothing but rivalry!
Today's issue over the football field...
...was just one of those rivalries.
You said we could share the field, but...
...that's not really the issue here!
That's how it looks.
As for the interschool tournament...
...it's an annual contest between
all the sports clubs of Nankatsu and Shutetsu.
It's like a festival.
In this city, it's a bigger deal than the sports festival!
What? That's amazing.
All our clubs are as good as Shutetsu's. Except for football.
That's why we're always a burden to the other clubs.
But with you on the team, we'll definitely put on a good show against Shutetsu!
Yes.
There!
Ugh, I missed!
Thanks for just now.
What? Don't mention it.
You made me a nice offer.
Ozora Tsubasa-kun.
I'm Roberto Hongo.
Nice to meet you.
Roberto Hongo!
I know you! I've watched your matches countless times!
Thank you!
I'm very glad to meet you too.
He smells of alcohol! He's just a drunk!
Hello. Are you Tsubasa's friend?
Yes.
I'm Roberto Hongo. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Do you also love football?
Yes, I do, but...
Is that so?
I absolutely love football!
He's clearly nuts.
How about I coach you until the interschool tournament?
A drunk coaching our team?!
Exactly. It's not like I'm coaching the sumo club.
Hold on!
Don't underestimate us just because we're an elementary school club!
Just because you put in a cross doesn't make you something special!
Anyone can do that!
Hey, hey. That's harsh.
What are you laughing at?! You're getting on my nerves.
Besides, nobody wants a drunk as a coach.
In that case...
...let me show you.
He took the ball so easily.
What's he doing?
Let's go!
What? It didn't even go in!
What?!
There it is.
Perfect!
A-Amazing!
So? Do you want me as coach?
I do, of course I do!
Absolutely! We're in your hands. Right, Tsubasa?
What?
There!
Tsubasa!
Could it be...
Hey, are you okay?
That was tough.
But you jump pretty well, though.
Exactly. I have high expectations for you, Tsubasa.
Really?
Yes.
Alright, once more.
You can't do it that quickly!
I can!
What?
He just saw my move and he's already trying it.
No wonder he improves so fast.
He's someone who's determined to replicate any technique he sees.
What?
He missed...
Are you okay?
He takes right after his father.
Isn't he, Captain Ozora?
Natsuko: Tsubasa ran off!
Just as I thought, my little footballer has slacked off again.
Though that's a very Tsubasa-like thing to do.
Captain!
So you were here.
We're approaching Japan.
Yes, I can finally go home.
By the way, how old is your son now?
He turned 10 this year and is in the final year of elementary school.
He's already 10?
So are you getting him a game as a trip gift this time?
No, he's already got his gift.
Besides, it's the most wonderful thing you could imagine.
Here...
Ugh... The ground and sky are spinning.
I'm dizzy...
Hey Tsubasa.
Even for you, this is way too fast.
No, it's not!
But it's going to get dark soon.
It's about time to head home.
Besides, I'm starving.
Not yet!
Roberto said he had high expectations.
We have no choice but to do this.
Even though he can't pull off the overhead kick yet...
...he's able to hit the post every time he tries.
He has amazing control.
# Ozora Tsubasa requests a match #
Take a good look.
Yes, at that goal!
That's our target!
This time we'll score!
Let's go!
Go in!
It went in!
Incredible!
I did it.
I did it!
You did it, Tsubasa!
You finally pulled off the overhead kick!
Yes!
Hooray, Tsubasa!
You're incredible, Tsubasa!
Wonder kid! Genius kid!
Brazilian expression of emotion...